<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dynamic Applied General Equilibrium Model on Lionel Ragot</title>
    <link>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/en/tags/dynamic-applied-general-equilibrium-model/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dynamic Applied General Equilibrium Model on Lionel Ragot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lionel-ragot.github.io/en/tags/dynamic-applied-general-equilibrium-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Que peut-on attendre d&#39;une assurance autonomie universelle dans le financement de la perte d&#39;autonomie? Evaluation à l&#39;aide d&#39;un modèle d&#39;équilibre général calculable</title>
      <link>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-22-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-22-en/</guid>
      <description>This article uses a computable general equilibrium model with overlapping generations to evaluate the implications that the implementation of mandatory long-term care insurance for financing the loss of independence could have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Immigration on an Ageing Welfare State: An Applied General Equilibrium Model for France</title>
      <link>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-16-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-16-en/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we evaluate, using a dynamic general equilibrium model, the contribution of migration policy in reducing the tax burden associated with the ageing population in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigration, vieillissement démographique et financement de la protection sociale</title>
      <link>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-11-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-11-en/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we evaluate, using a dynamic general equilibrium model, the contribution of migration policy in reducing the tax burden associated with the aging population in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should the US have locked heaven’s door?</title>
      <link>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-09-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-09-en/</guid>
      <description>This paper examines the economic impact of the second great immigration wave (1945–2000) on the US economy. Contrary to recent studies, we show that immigration induced important net gains and small redistributive effects among natives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiscalité environnementale et sensibilité écologique des consommateurs</title>
      <link>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-01-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lionel-ragot.github.io/11-00-01-en/</guid>
      <description>This paper describes a dynamic applied general equilibrium model, with perfect foresight, designed for clarifying the questions concerning taxation and the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
